<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>book-review on Suraj Deshmukh</title>
    <link>https://suraj.io/tags/book-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in book-review on Suraj Deshmukh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 11:30:07 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://suraj.io/tags/book-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: Contemporary world vis-à-vis 1984 by George Orwell</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/opinion-contemporary-world-1984-by-george-orwell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 11:30:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/opinion-contemporary-world-1984-by-george-orwell/</guid>
      <description>The story in the book showcases a dystopian world in the year 1984, where there are only three countries in the world, and all of them are in a constant power struggle. All three countries have a totalitarian, oligarchic government of their own. But the story in the book is from a country called Oceania, which is ruled by a party called Ingsoc or English Socialism. This blog is about the similarities of the world in the book 1984 and today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review of Einstein: His Life and Universe</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/book-review-einstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 11:30:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/book-review-einstein/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished this book Einstein: His Life and Universe by Walter Isaacson. And here are my thoughts on the book.
It&amp;rsquo;s a book that brings the image of Einstein to life.
Although the book is a biography, it makes a reasonable effort in explaining the physics behind his theories of relativity, photoelectric effect and quantum physics. Physics in the book can be intimidating to someone coming from the non-Scientific background.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>