<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on Suraj Deshmukh</title>
    <link>https://suraj.io/categories/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Suraj Deshmukh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 01:00:51 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://suraj.io/categories/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Single node Kubernetes Cluster on Fedora with SELinux enabled</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/single-node-k8s-fedora-selinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 01:00:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/single-node-k8s-fedora-selinux/</guid>
      <description>Start a single node fedora machine, using whatever method but I have used this Vagrantfile to do it:
# -*- mode: ruby -*- # vi: set ft=ruby : Vagrant.configure(&amp;quot;2&amp;quot;) do |config| config.vm.define &amp;quot;fedora&amp;quot; do |fedora| fedora.vm.box = &amp;quot;fedora/28-cloud-base&amp;quot; config.vm.hostname = &amp;quot;fedora&amp;quot; end config.vm.provider &amp;quot;virtualbox&amp;quot; do |virtualbox, override| virtualbox.memory = 4096 virtualbox.cpus = 4 end config.vm.provision &amp;quot;shell&amp;quot;, privileged: false, inline: &amp;lt;&amp;lt;-SHELL echo &#39;127.0.0.1 localhost&#39; | cat - /etc/hosts &amp;gt; temp &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo mv temp /etc/hosts SHELL end  Now start it and ssh into it:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HostPath volumes and it&#39;s problems</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/k8s-hostpat-nuke-nodes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 01:00:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/k8s-hostpat-nuke-nodes/</guid>
      <description>This post will demonstrate how Kubernetes HostPath volumes can help you get access to the Kubernetes nodes. Atleast you can play with the filesystem of the node on which you pod is scheduled on. You can get access to other containers running on the host, certificates of the kubelet, etc.
I have a 3-master and 3-node cluster and setup using this script, running in a Vagrant environment.
All the nodes are in ready state:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change namespaces in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/changing-k8s-ns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:00:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/changing-k8s-ns/</guid>
      <description>There is no easy way to change namespace in Kubernetes using kubectl command line utility. But here are some commands that you can alias in your bashrc file so that it&amp;rsquo;s just a single command that you can use to change the namespace in the Kubernetes cluster.
Change namespace Let&amp;rsquo;s see step by step what goes in to change the namespace. So the first step is to find the context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using private container registries from minikube</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/private-registry-from-minikube/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 19:32:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/private-registry-from-minikube/</guid>
      <description>I am doing Kubernetes native development using minikube. And for doing that I had to download a Container image that is available in internally hosted private container registry.
On the configuration side of doing that you will need to create Kubernetes Secret of type docker-registry. And now refer that secret you just created in your Pod manifest under pod.spec.imagePullSecrets. For more info follow the tutorial in Kubernetes docs on Pull an Image from a Private Registry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Pods using Kubelet on Fedora</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/static-pods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 13:10:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/static-pods/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to try out Standalone Kubelet Tutorial of Kelsey Hightower by myself but I could not follow it as it is, because it was firstly on GCE and secondly it uses CoreOS, but since I am very familiar to Fedora I thought of following that tutorial on it. To get a quick setup of a fresh Fedora machine use Vagrant. I have used Vagrantfile available here.
This blog is only replacement of section Install the Standalone Kubelet in tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Learning resources</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/k8s-learning-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 23:12:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/k8s-learning-resources/</guid>
      <description>Following is the list of all the places you can learn Kubernetes from:
 Scalable Microservices with Kubernetes - Video tutorial Fundamentals of Containers, Kubernetes, and Red Hat OpenShift - Video tutorial Kubernetes By Example - DIY tutorial Learn Kubernetes using Interactive Browser-Based Scenarios - DIY tutorial in your own web browser Interactive Learning Portal for OpenShift - DIY tutorial in your own web browser Kubernetes docs - Textual DIY docs Kubernetes API reference v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling local development with Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/enabling-local-development-with-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 15:57:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/enabling-local-development-with-k8s/</guid>
      <description>I want to show how you can enable Kubernetes in your day to day development workflow. So that you get the feel of production deployment locally from day 1.
I have a flask application which I am working on. The basic directory structure looks like this:
$ ll total 24 -rw-rw-r--. 1 foo foo 427 Apr 23 16:23 app.py -rw-rw-r--. 1 foo foo 201 Apr 23 16:55 docker-compose.yml -rw-rw-r--. 1 foo foo 363 Apr 23 16:21 Dockerfile -rwxrwxr-x.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick PV for local Kubernetes cluster</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/quick-pv-for-local-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 23:56:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/quick-pv-for-local-k8s/</guid>
      <description>I do lot of Kubernetes related work either on minikube or local OpenShift cluster setup in a VM. Often I need to create a PersistentVolumeClaim a.k.a. pvc. But to use pvc you have to have a PersistentVolume or pv defined.
Enter into the machine running k8s If using minikube you can do
minikube ssh  Create a local directory for storage mkdir /tmp/pv0001 chmod 777 /tmp/pv0001  If you are on a machine that has SELinux enabled do the following</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k8s on CRI-O - single node</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/using-crio-with-k8s-single-node/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:11:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/using-crio-with-k8s-single-node/</guid>
      <description>Here is a single node Kubernetes on CRI-O. This setup is done on Fedora 25.
Installing OS dependencies dnf -y install \ go \ git \ btrfs-progs-devel \ device-mapper-devel \ glib2-devel \ glibc-devel \ glibc-static \ gpgme-devel \ libassuan-devel \ libgpg-error-devel \ libseccomp-devel \ libselinux-devel \ pkgconfig \ wget \ etcd \ iptables  Creating go environment cd ~ mkdir -p ~/go export GOPATH=~/go export GOBIN=$GOPATH/bin export PATH=$PATH:$GOBIN echo &#39;GOPATH=~/go&#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>