<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>non-tech on Suraj Deshmukh</title>
    <link>https://suraj.io/tags/non-tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in non-tech on Suraj Deshmukh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 11:05:07 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suraj.io/tags/non-tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fight Your Instincts — Your Default Behaviour is Hurting You</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/2021/10/dont-be-default/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2021 11:05:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/2021/10/dont-be-default/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Johannes Plenio on Unsplash.
We behave in a certain way. It is shaped by various factors like our upbringing, environment, privilege, etc. But most of the time, it is shaped by our instincts. Until pointed out, we continue to act with our instincts. This instinct-driven behavior is our default behavior.
I am making a case that anyone who has never rebelled against or resisted their default behavior will find it hard to achieve success in this world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learnings from &#39;Atomic Habits&#39;</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/2021/10/atomic-habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2021 09:21:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/2021/10/atomic-habits/</guid>
      <description>Yet again, this is not a book review, instead, go ahead and read the book Atomic Habits. I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it enough.
Written by James Clear, the book is not a theoretical text just talking about habits. Rather, it is a handbook that goes into the depth of how habits form, how they can be fostered, how human evolution hinders good habit formation in today&amp;rsquo;s world, etc. It gives you practical tips and actions on setting good habits and breaking bad ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unchanging Contexts and Degrading Productivity</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/2021/09/unchanging-context/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 17:09:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/2021/09/unchanging-context/</guid>
      <description>Photo by daan evers on Unsplash.
Everything feels like work since the pandemic began. But the feeling has been more gnawing for the last couple of months. I have been working from home since 2018, but that was different! The work from home since the pandemic began is pretty adverse.
The Tragedy of Lost Contexts Everything happens from the same place, things like work, seeing friends, entertainment, conferences, meetup, reading for fun, side project, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learnings from &#39;Sapiens&#39;</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/2021/08/sapiens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 10:45:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/2021/08/sapiens/</guid>
      <description>This is not a book review. Instead, this is a book recommendation. Please go ahead and buy this book. If you cannot afford to buy the book, please reach out to me. I will help you buy it⁕. This blog will give you a general idea of what this book is about. I will provide some background about the book and the author, followed by the notes from the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Devices</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/2021/06/reading-devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2021 01:45:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/2021/06/reading-devices/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Alvan Nee on Unsplash.
I use different devices for consuming content from disparate streams, even for books. This post discusses each method&amp;rsquo;s various pros and cons and what fits best in what kind of circumstance.
You can refer to the table at the end of the post, where I have broken down each comparison aspect.
Physical Books This method of consuming knowledge became prevalent with Gutenburg&amp;rsquo;s printing press. Getting a new book always gives you that dopamine rush since it has a sense of newness, new cover, the smell of paper, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learnings from &#39;The Psychology of Money&#39;</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/2021/05/learnings-psychology-of-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 12:15:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/2021/05/learnings-psychology-of-money/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Morgan Housel on Unsplash.
Synopsis of the Book The Psychology of Money, written by Morgan Housel, published in 2020, could be categorised under Psychology, Finance, and Nonfiction. The author wrote an article three years ago which got a lot of traffic hence decided to write a book out of it. Last year I saw that the book was recommended by many folks in my network and on Twitter. All of the recommenders were highly impressed by the book and spoke intensely of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Religious Rituals Don&#39;t Scale With Population</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/2021/04/rituals-dont-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 07:07:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/2021/04/rituals-dont-scale/</guid>
      <description>There are numerous Hindu festivals celebrated throughout the year. The rituals associated with each festival differ to the extent these festivals are celebrated. I am here to recount the environmental impact of the customs Hindus are involved in.
Although a ritual associated with each festival and its effect on the environment is insignificant on a small scale. But with Hindus in India being close to a billion (966 million as per the 2011 census, with the population growth rate that might be almost a billion), these rituals don&amp;rsquo;t scale very well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How we manage Kubernetes Bangalore Meetup?</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/2021/03/k8s-blr-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 07:07:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/2021/03/k8s-blr-meetup/</guid>
      <description>I took the reins of the Kubernetes Bangalore Meetup back in 2017. I have been organising the meetup since then. Earlier with Suraj Narwade, Aditya Konarde and now with Prakash Mishra. Over time the meetup has grown a lot, now it boasts about 5000 members. Organising meetup earlier was a straightforward affair, especially with Narwade and Konarde being my colleagues and friends. We could chat about the upcoming meetup at any time we would like, and it was all spontaneous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Compounder Skills</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/2021/03/compounder-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 07:07:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/2021/03/compounder-skills/</guid>
      <description>There are specific skills which you should acquire early on in your life. These skills are the foundational skills. Everything you do after developing these skills becomes better, faster and easier. I call these skills Compounder Skills. Derived from the term &amp;ldquo;Compound Interest&amp;rdquo;. The idea is that once you are laced with a particular compounder skill, you can apply it in various fields of your life. An example of a compounder skill that most humans get exposed to is &amp;ldquo;school education&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importance of Typing Skills</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/2021/02/typing-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 07:07:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/2021/02/typing-skills/</guid>
      <description>Yes, today&amp;rsquo;s topic is typing skills. I think not many people stress about it, but it is a very underrated skill, yet useful in our daily lives.
I typed the most organic way anybody starts doing it. Look at the keyboard when you are typing and fix mistakes after looking at the monitor. I moved my hand around on the keyboard and only used index fingers to touch the keys as if other fingers were glued together away from the keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Knowledge Management Journey</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/2021/02/kms-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 09:07:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/2021/02/kms-journey/</guid>
      <description>Photo by Patrick Tomasso on Unsplash.
If you are reading this, you are definitely a Knowledge Worker. As Knowledge Workers, we rely a lot on the information we know or have access to for our day to day work. Occasionally, we will do the same thing twice, face the situation more than once, want to read that reference or try to understand the insights mentioned in that one particular blog. How do you keep track of such information?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book: How Innovation Works</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/2021/02/book-hiw-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 21:43:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/2021/02/book-hiw-learnings/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently finished reading the book: &amp;ldquo;How Innovation Works: And Why It Flourishes in Freedom&amp;rdquo; by Matt Ridley. The book was published less than a year ago in May 2020, and it is a short read of fewer than four hundred pages. I am not sure how to categorise this book, it probably falls into business, science and/or technological history.
While listening to Naval Ravikant&amp;rsquo;s podcast, I found this book when Matt Ridley, the author, was a guest in one episode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: How to Take Smart Notes</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/book-review-how-to-take-smart-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 21:30:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/book-review-how-to-take-smart-notes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction How to Take Smart Notes: One Simple Technique to Boost Writing, Learning and Thinking – for Students, Academics and Nonfiction Book Writers by Sönke Ahrens is a small (171 pages) non-fiction genre book. The book is a manual explaining Zettlekasten method designed by Niklas Luhmann. Sönke has used straightforward and simple English to explain the concepts. For anyone who is a knowledge curator or wishes to publish non-fictional content in any form (text, video or audio), this book is a must-read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Algorithms to Live by — The Computer Science of Human Decisions</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/book-review-algorithms-to-live-by-the-computer-science-of-human-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 17:30:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/book-review-algorithms-to-live-by-the-computer-science-of-human-decisions/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The book &amp;ldquo;Algorithms to Live by — The Computer Science of Human Decisions&amp;rdquo; is written by &amp;ldquo;Brian Christian and Tom Griffiths&amp;rdquo;. It fits into the genre non-fiction, psychology and computer science. The book is written lucidly. If you have a background in computer science, then this book is easy to follow. The book creates analogies of computer science algorithms with real-life situations. I felt that some metaphors sound good in reading than their application, so if you plan on applying the things explained in the book directly to your life, they might not work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review: Getting Things Done</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/book-review-getting-things-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 16:00:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/book-review-getting-things-done/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Recently I completed the book called Getting Things Done: The Art of Stress-free Productivity by David Allen. I read the book on my kindle e-reader device, and as the name suggests, it is a self-help category book and about three hundred pages long.
The book is an extraordinary walkthrough of how to set up a system that will help you navigate your daily tasks without missing any of them. This system then enables you to patch up the crevices of your memory from which day-to-day tasks fall through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opinion: Contemporary world vis-à-vis 1984 by George Orwell</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/opinion-contemporary-world-1984-by-george-orwell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 11:30:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/opinion-contemporary-world-1984-by-george-orwell/</guid>
      <description>The book 1984 was written by Geroge Orwell in 1949 as an attempt to demonstrate how democraries can also fall into the trap of totalitarianism. The story in the book showcases a dystopian world in the year 1984, where there are only three countries in the world, and all of them are in a constant power struggle. All three countries have a totalitarian, oligarchic government of their own. But the story in the book is from a country called Oceania, which is ruled by a party called Ingsoc or English Socialism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review of Einstein: His Life and Universe</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/book-review-einstein/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 11:30:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/book-review-einstein/</guid>
      <description>I recently finished this book Einstein: His Life and Universe by Walter Isaacson. And here are my thoughts on the book.
It&amp;rsquo;s a book that brings the image of Einstein to life.
Although the book is a biography, it makes a reasonable effort in explaining the physics behind his theories of relativity, photoelectric effect and quantum physics. Physics in the book can be intimidating to someone coming from the non-Scientific background.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
