<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Suraj Deshmukh</title>
    <link>http://suraj.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Suraj Deshmukh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:00:51 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://suraj.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Change namespaces in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/changing-k8s-ns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:00:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/changing-k8s-ns/</guid>
      <description>There is no easy way to change namespace in Kubernetes using kubectl command line utility. But here are some commands that you can alias in your bashrc file so that it&amp;rsquo;s just a single command that you can use to change the namespace in the Kubernetes cluster.
Change namespace Let&amp;rsquo;s see step by step what goes in to change the namespace. So the first step is to find the context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prometheus with existing application on OpenShift</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/using-prometheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 08:00:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/using-prometheus/</guid>
      <description>This post is very specific to OpenShift and how you can have an application exposing prometheus metrics to be scraped by a prometheus running in the same cluster.
Requirements Setting up cluster I have done it using the oc cluster up, read about how to do this here. You could also setup a local OpenShift cluster by running minishift, read about setting up minishift here.
Downloading Kedge The configurations defined for setting up this cluster is written in a format that is understood by a tool called Kedge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on talk - Advanced testing in golang by Mitchell Hashimoto</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/advanced-golang-testing-mitchellh-talk-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 02:21:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/advanced-golang-testing-mitchellh-talk-notes/</guid>
      <description>Test Fixtures  &amp;ldquo;go test&amp;rdquo; sets pwd as package directory  Test Helpers  should never return an error they should access to the *testing.T object call t.Helper() in the beginning (works only for go1.9+) for things reqiuiring clean up return closures  Configurability  Unconfigurable behavior is often a point of difficulty for tests. e.g. ports, timeouts, paths. Over-parameterize structs to allow tests to fine-tune their behavior It&amp;rsquo;s ok to make these configs unexported so only tests can set them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methods that satisfy interfaces in golang</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/golang-methods-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 08:00:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/golang-methods-interfaces/</guid>
      <description>Pointer receiver For a struct User with a method Work with pointer receiver.
type User struct { Name string Period int } func (u *User) Work() { fmt.Println(u.Name, &amp;quot;has worked for&amp;quot;, u.Period, &amp;quot;hrs.&amp;quot;) } func main() { uval := User{&amp;quot;UserVal&amp;quot;, 5} uval.Work() pval := &amp;amp;User{&amp;quot;UserPtr&amp;quot;, 6} pval.Work() }  See on go playground.
output:
UserVal has worked for 5 hrs. UserPtr has worked for 6 hrs.  If we call this method on value type object uval it works, and obviously it works with pointer type object pval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vscode Shortcuts</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/vscode-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 08:00:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/vscode-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>This post has shortcuts that are generic and golang specific as well. This post will edited from time to time.
Shortcuts  Toggle side bar  Ctrl + B
 Project explorer in side bar  Ctrl + Shift + E
 Project wide search in side bar  Ctrl + Shift + F
 Source control in side bar  Ctrl + Shift + G
 Copy entire line  Ctrl + C (without any selection)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using private container registries from minikube</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/private-registry-from-minikube/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 19:32:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/private-registry-from-minikube/</guid>
      <description>I am doing Kubernetes native development using minikube. And for doing that I had to download a Container image that is available in internally hosted private container registry.
On the configuration side of doing that you will need to create Kubernetes Secret of type docker-registry. And now refer that secret you just created in your Pod manifest under pod.spec.imagePullSecrets. For more info follow the tutorial in Kubernetes docs on Pull an Image from a Private Registry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Static Pods using Kubelet on Fedora</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/static-pods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 13:10:14 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/static-pods/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to try out Standalone Kubelet Tutorial of Kelsey Hightower by myself but I could not follow it as it is, because it was firstly on GCE and secondly it uses CoreOS, but since I am very familiar to Fedora I thought of following that tutorial on it. To get a quick setup of a fresh Fedora machine use Vagrant. I have used Vagrantfile available here.
This blog is only replacement of section Install the Standalone Kubelet in tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharing Vagrant Box offline</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/move-vagrant-boxes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 10:43:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/move-vagrant-boxes/</guid>
      <description>If you have some box that was downloaded on your machine from Atlas but now you wanna share it on other machines and you don&amp;rsquo;t have internet to download it, how do you share it?
You will need to export the box from machine that has it downloaded already. So on machine with boxes:
$ vagrant box list centos/7 (libvirt, 1610.01) centos/7 (libvirt, 1704.01) fedora/25-cloud-base (libvirt, 20161122) fedora/26-cloud-base (libvirt, 20170705)  I wanted to share fedora/26-cloud-base box to another machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add new Maps to Counter Strike</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/add-new-map-to-cs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 16:03:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/add-new-map-to-cs/</guid>
      <description>If you are playing Counter Strike on Steam on linux you might be wondering how do I install new maps in the game. So here are steps to install maps.
All the game maps for Counter Strike - Condition Zero are stored in following path:
~/.local/share/Steam/steamapps/common/Half-Life/czero/maps  Format of the map files is .bsp.
So download the map files from over internet and then put in this location and now you should be able to see the maps in game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of Kubernetes Bangalore meetup event report</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/list-all-k8s-meetups/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 15:51:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/list-all-k8s-meetups/</guid>
      <description>List of all the event reports from Kubernetes Bangalore meetup.
 April 2017 May 2017 June 2017 July 2017 Kubernetes 2nd Birthday Celebration August 2017 September 2017 October 2017 November 2017  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Learning resources</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/k8s-learning-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 23:12:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/k8s-learning-resources/</guid>
      <description>Following is the list of all the places you can learn Kubernetes from:
 Scalable Microservices with Kubernetes - Video tutorial Fundamentals of Containers, Kubernetes, and Red Hat OpenShift - Video tutorial Kubernetes By Example - DIY tutorial Learn Kubernetes using Interactive Browser-Based Scenarios - DIY tutorial in your own web browser Interactive Learning Portal for OpenShift - DIY tutorial in your own web browser Kubernetes docs - Textual DIY docs Kubernetes API reference v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Kubernetes Meetup July 2017</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/blr-k8s-meetup-july-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 22:46:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/blr-k8s-meetup-july-2017/</guid>
      <description>This edition of meetup was held at Nexus Ventures by folks at OpenEBS on July 8th 2017, which started on a lovely Saturday morning.
Kiran Mova set the floor rolling with his talk on Hyperconverged version of OpenEBS with Kubernetes. Where he talked about containerized storage vs traditional storage, instead of building clustering into OpenEBS how they are leveraging Kubernetes&amp;rsquo;s capabilities to do clustering.
He also explained difference between various storage providers viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Node setup</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/node-no-sudo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 22:50:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/node-no-sudo/</guid>
      <description>Make sure you have npm installed.
$ sudo dnf -y install npm Package npm-1:3.10.10-1.6.10.3.1.fc25.x86_64 is already installed, skipping. Dependencies resolved. Nothing to do. Complete!  Taken from this post.
mkdir &amp;quot;${HOME}/.npm-packages&amp;quot; echo &#39;prefix=${HOME}/.npm-packages&#39; | tee -a ~/.npmrc echo &#39; #====================================== # npm related stuff NPM_PACKAGES=&amp;quot;${HOME}/.npm-packages&amp;quot; PATH=&amp;quot;$NPM_PACKAGES/bin:$PATH&amp;quot; # Unset manpath so we can inherit from /etc/manpath via the `manpath` command unset MANPATH # delete if you already modified MANPATH elsewhere in your config export MANPATH=&amp;quot;$NPM_PACKAGES/share/man:$(manpath)&amp;quot; #====================================== &#39; | tee -a ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Kubernetes Meetup May 2017</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/blr-k8s-meetup-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 02:21:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/blr-k8s-meetup-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;One does not simply deploy containers to production&amp;rdquo;
With the rising craze around the container community in Bangalore and relative lack in awareness around different container technologies like Kubernetes and OpenShift, an effort was made in imparting knowledge in this direction.
So, this time around newbies were targeted for the Kubernetes Meetup.
With the above objective, it was decided to have a Kubernetes 101 workshop at Red Hat Bangalore office on May 21, 2017 to familiarize people with concepts of Kubernetes and OpenShift and their usage and relevance as container orchestration tools for managing application deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enabling local development with Kubernetes</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/enabling-local-development-with-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 15:57:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/enabling-local-development-with-k8s/</guid>
      <description>I want to show how you can enable Kubernetes in your day to day development workflow. So that you get the feel of production deployment locally from day 1.
I have a flask application which I am working on. The basic directory structure looks like this:
$ ll total 24 -rw-rw-r--. 1 foo foo 427 Apr 23 16:23 app.py -rw-rw-r--. 1 foo foo 201 Apr 23 16:55 docker-compose.yml -rw-rw-r--. 1 foo foo 363 Apr 23 16:21 Dockerfile -rwxrwxr-x.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick PV for local Kubernetes cluster</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/quick-pv-for-local-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 23:56:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/quick-pv-for-local-k8s/</guid>
      <description>I do lot of Kubernetes related work either on minikube or local OpenShift cluster setup in a VM. Often I need to create a PersistentVolumeClaim a.k.a. pvc. But to use pvc you have to have a PersistentVolume or pv defined.
Enter into the machine running k8s If using minikube you can do
minikube ssh  Create a local directory for storage mkdir /tmp/pv0001 chmod 777 /tmp/pv0001  If you are on a machine that has SELinux enabled do the following</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Kubernetes Meetup April 2017</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/blr-k8s-meetup-april-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 14:31:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/blr-k8s-meetup-april-2017/</guid>
      <description>Like many Saturday mornings, Red Hat Bangalore office was once again abuzz with enthusiasm on 8th of April, for hosting yet another successful chapter of Bangalore Kubernetes Meetup. The Meetup had a good turnaround of about 40 people who gave up on their early morning saturday sleep to attend it despite the sweltering hot season and in line were four awesome talks.
Suraj Deshmukh set the stage with his opening talk, Kubernetes on CRI-O, wherein he explained different jargons like OCI, CRI, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k8s on CRI-O - single node</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/using-crio-with-k8s-single-node/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 00:11:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/using-crio-with-k8s-single-node/</guid>
      <description>Here is a single node Kubernetes on CRI-O. This setup is done on Fedora 25.
Installing OS dependencies dnf -y install \ go \ git \ btrfs-progs-devel \ device-mapper-devel \ glib2-devel \ glibc-devel \ glibc-static \ gpgme-devel \ libassuan-devel \ libgpg-error-devel \ libseccomp-devel \ libselinux-devel \ pkgconfig \ wget \ etcd \ iptables  Creating go environment cd ~ mkdir -p ~/go export GOPATH=~/go export GOBIN=$GOPATH/bin export PATH=$PATH:$GOBIN echo &#39;GOPATH=~/go&#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TODOs for new project</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/starting-a-new-opensource-project-requirements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2017 18:19:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/starting-a-new-opensource-project-requirements/</guid>
      <description>When starting a new open source project, apart from coding following are the things that need to be done.
Docs  README LICENSE How to install? How to use? Code of conduct guidelines Copyright Issue template like .github in repo.  Developer docs  How to install for developer? Developer docs Contribution guidelines Team meetings info Team communication channels Issue label guidelines Coding standards Code placement doc, or something that explains the way code is ordered Design document  Development  Makefile Unit tests Functional tests Coverage check CI for automatic tests Distro based package  This is just few things that I could think of, please suggest if you know more in comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rpm Notes</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/rpm-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 10:35:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/rpm-notes/</guid>
      <description>Setup of the system for building rpms $ dnf -y install fedora-packager fedora-review $ sudo usermod -a -G mock vagrant $ fedora-packager-setup $ kinit surajd@FEDORAPROJECT.ORG  My Notes  Start reading from: Fedora packager&amp;rsquo;s guide Some macros come from redhat-rpm-config and fedora-rpm-macros.  $ sudo rpm -ql redhat-rpm-config-45-1.fc25.noarch   To see all macros on the system:  $ rpm --showrc   Koji - fedora build system fedora uses fedpkg for doing builds, while rpmbuild is for CentOS To get general info about the package  $ rpm -qip .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git Notes</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/git-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 22:03:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/git-notes/</guid>
      <description>Notes about using git.
Tips and tricks Switch branches $ git checkout &amp;lt;branch&amp;gt;  status $ git status -sb  Show status in short format and also give branch info
show $ git show  Shows log message and diff about the commit you are on.
log $ git log -L 70,100:pkg/transformer/kubernetes/kubernetes.go  Get logs on file between line numbers.
$ git log --graph --abbrev-commit  Show graph in logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intellij Shortcuts</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/intellij-shortcuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 14:41:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/intellij-shortcuts/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is a living document and will be updated as I discover new things.
Shortcuts  Ctrl + Shift + A  Find any action in IDE
 Ctrl + Shift + F  Find in Path
 Alt + 1  Open project navigator. You can search here, just start typing here, after the project navigator window is opened.
 Shift + Insert in Project window  Here you can add new file to the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packaging &#39;kompose&#39; for centos paas sig</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/packaging-kompose-for-centos-paas-sig/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 14:16:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/packaging-kompose-for-centos-paas-sig/</guid>
      <description>Note: This is a living document and will be updated from time to time.
Following are steps to package kompose for CentOS PAAS SIG. CentOS PAAS SIG is a repository of packages where rpms related to OpenShift and eco-system around it are delivered.
Setup your machine Install packages needed
sudo yum update -y &amp;amp;&amp;amp; \ sudo yum install -y epel-release &amp;amp;&amp;amp; \ sudo yum install -y rpm-build go redhat-rpm-config make koji \ gcc byobu rpmlint rpmdevtools centos-packager  Setup certs</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing &#39;fedora&#39; and &#39;CentOS&#39; kompose package</title>
      <link>http://suraj.io/post/test-kompose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Mar 2017 00:31:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://suraj.io/post/test-kompose/</guid>
      <description>I generally do kompose package testing for fedora and CentOS. So here are the steps I follow.
Fedora For respective fedora version use the tag respectively for e.g. 25 for fedora 25.
Starting the environment:
docker run -it registry.fedoraproject.org/fedora:26 bash  Running tests:
# Inside the container # Pull packages from the testing repository dnf --enablerepo updates-testing -y install kompose # Check the kompose version kompose version # Install the testing dependencies dnf install -y jq make # Pull the git repository to run the functional tests git clone https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>