<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>meetup on Suraj Deshmukh</title>
    <link>https://suraj.io/tags/meetup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in meetup on Suraj Deshmukh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 07:07:07 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://suraj.io/tags/meetup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How we manage Kubernetes Bangalore Meetup?</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/2021/03/k8s-blr-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 07:07:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/2021/03/k8s-blr-meetup/</guid>
      <description>I took the reins of the Kubernetes Bangalore Meetup back in 2017. I have been organising the meetup since then. Earlier with Suraj Narwade, Aditya Konarde and now with Prakash Mishra. Over time the meetup has grown a lot, now it boasts about 5000 members. Organising meetup earlier was a straightforward affair, especially with Narwade and Konarde being my colleagues and friends. We could chat about the upcoming meetup at any time we would like, and it was all spontaneous.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suraj Deshmukh&#39;s talks at conferences</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/surajd-talks-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 01:00:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/surajd-talks-links/</guid>
      <description>PSP and Beyond - Kubernetes Bangalore Meetup June 2021    Hardening Kubernetes by Securing Pods - Rootconf 2019    State of Kubernetes Meetups - DevOpsDays India 2017    Making Kubernetes Simple For Developers - Rootconf 2017    Taking docker-compose to Production - Gophercon 2017 Lightening talk Watch from 55m59s
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Bangalore March 2019 Event Report</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/k8s-blr-event-report-2019-03-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 01:00:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/k8s-blr-event-report-2019-03-16/</guid>
      <description>The Kubernetes Bangalore Meetup was organized at Arvind Internet on Feb 16th 2019. The agenda for the meetup was to teach Kubernetes to the beginners.
Meetup agenda can be found here.
The moments from Meetup:
We go online in sometime here https://t.co/FkwgOx0Tm4
&amp;mdash; Kubernetes Bangalore (@k8sBLR) March 16, 2019  .@pmishra1598 kick started the Meetup by explaining what #Kubernetes is! Currently clarifying what a pod is. pic.twitter.com/Ny7bN9c62x
&amp;mdash; Kubernetes Bangalore (@k8sBLR) March 16, 2019  Huge turnout at today&amp;#39;s meetup it&amp;#39;s on 🔥🔥 pic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of Kubernetes Bangalore meetup event report</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/list-all-k8s-meetups/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 15:51:16 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/list-all-k8s-meetups/</guid>
      <description>List of all the event reports from Kubernetes Bangalore meetup.
 April 2017 May 2017 June 2017 July 2017 Kubernetes 2nd Birthday Celebration August 2017 September 2017 October 2017 November 2017  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Kubernetes Meetup July 2017</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/blr-k8s-meetup-july-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 22:46:40 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/blr-k8s-meetup-july-2017/</guid>
      <description>This edition of meetup was held at Nexus Ventures by folks at OpenEBS on July 8th 2017, which started on a lovely Saturday morning.
Kiran Mova set the floor rolling with his talk on Hyperconverged version of OpenEBS with Kubernetes. Where he talked about containerized storage vs traditional storage, instead of building clustering into OpenEBS how they are leveraging Kubernetes&amp;rsquo;s capabilities to do clustering.
He also explained difference between various storage providers viz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Kubernetes Meetup May 2017</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/blr-k8s-meetup-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 02:21:49 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/blr-k8s-meetup-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;One does not simply deploy containers to production&amp;rdquo;
With the rising craze around the container community in Bangalore and relative lack in awareness around different container technologies like Kubernetes and OpenShift, an effort was made in imparting knowledge in this direction.
So, this time around newbies were targeted for the Kubernetes Meetup.
With the above objective, it was decided to have a Kubernetes 101 workshop at Red Hat Bangalore office on May 21, 2017 to familiarize people with concepts of Kubernetes and OpenShift and their usage and relevance as container orchestration tools for managing application deployments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Kubernetes Meetup April 2017</title>
      <link>https://suraj.io/post/blr-k8s-meetup-april-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Apr 2017 14:31:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://suraj.io/post/blr-k8s-meetup-april-2017/</guid>
      <description>Like many Saturday mornings, Red Hat Bangalore office was once again abuzz with enthusiasm on 8th of April, for hosting yet another successful chapter of Bangalore Kubernetes Meetup. The Meetup had a good turnaround of about 40 people who gave up on their early morning saturday sleep to attend it despite the sweltering hot season and in line were four awesome talks.
Suraj Deshmukh set the stage with his opening talk, Kubernetes on CRI-O, wherein he explained different jargons like OCI, CRI, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
